<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>analysis on Brian Weinstein</title>
    <link>https://www.brianweinstein.co/tags/analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in analysis on Brian Weinstein</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brianweinstein.co/tags/analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In defense of “nothing interesting”</title>
      <link>https://www.brianweinstein.co/posts/20200219-in-defense-of-nothing-interesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brianweinstein.co/posts/20200219-in-defense-of-nothing-interesting/</guid>
      <description>A tribute to useful, but less interesting research findings originally published on Medium   A tribute to useful, but less interesting research findings
 A few years ago as a Data Scientist I was presenting to co-workers an analysis I’d been working on. The presentation went fine and the work was well-received, but I could tell the group was a little underwhelmed. Towards the end of the presentation, one co-worker asked, “Did you find anything that surprised you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking like a president</title>
      <link>https://www.brianweinstein.co/posts/20161003-debate-nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brianweinstein.co/posts/20161003-debate-nlp/</guid>
      <description>Natural language processing on the first 2016 presidential debate originally published on Fouriest Series  Natural language processing on the first 2016 presidential debate The first debate in the 2016 presidential race was held on September 26. It’s no secret that Clinton and Trump are running on drastically different platforms, but how do they compare when it comes to their speech patterns and word choice? To quantify this, I dug into the data, using the debate transcript and natural language processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the frozen yogurt shop closest to each Manhattan apartment</title>
      <link>https://www.brianweinstein.co/posts/20160531-froyo-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brianweinstein.co/posts/20160531-froyo-nyc/</guid>
      <description>originally published on Fouriest Series  I love frozen yogurt. When I first moved to New York three years ago, I lived only 1/8th of a mile from the closest froyo shop. The convenience of this 4-minute walk is something I neither appreciated nor utilized enough at the time.
After moving to Harlem last year, it’s been harder than ever to satisfy my near-constant craving for this cold candy soup — I’m now a 24-minute walk to the nearest frozen yogurt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
